I need you to pick a tablecloth
我要你来选张桌布
Aren't they both the same?
两张不一样么？
-w-
-w-
I don't even know why I asked!
真不懂为啥我要问你！
So, have you picked out a dress yet?
话说，你选好裙子了么？
What's the point?
有意义么？
Who cares about the dance if Blake isn't going?
谁要管一个Blake都不来的舞会？
Oh, don't worry, she's going
别担心，她会来的
Weiss!
Weiss！
I thought we agreed, no doilies!
不是说好别用桌巾嘛！
If I don't get doilies, you don't get fog machines
要我别用桌巾，那你也别弄烟雾机
Your dance is gonna have fog machines?
你们的舞会要用上烟雾机？
We were thinking about it
我们正在考虑呢
That's pretty cool
挺酷的嘛
You ladies all excited for dress up?
女士们也迫不及待要打扮了？
Pfft, yeah, right!
- - 呵呵，是啊
Laugh all you want, I'll be turning heads tomorrow night
你们尽管笑，看我明晚回头率爆表
What are you two wearing?
你们俩穿什么？
Uhh..this?
呃..这套？
Ignore him, for he knows not what he says
快无视他，他不懂自己在说什么
Hey, I may have moved to Mistral, but I grew up in Vacuo
喂，虽然搬到寒风了，但我是维基亚长大的
It's not exactly a shirt-and-tie kinda place
那地方不怎么注重仪表
Yeah, we've noticed
是啊，看出来了
So..what does Blake think of all this?
那么..Blake对这些怎么想？
She still being all, you know..Blakey?
她依然还是，那个..老样子？
Obviously
显而易见
I still can't think of a way to change her mind
我还是想不出办法让她改变主意
Guys
伙伴们
Trust me
相信我
Blake will be at the dance tomorrow
Blake明天会来舞会的
-w-
-w-
0w0
0w0
Hello~
好呀~
What are you..
你干嘛..
We need to talk
我们得谈谈
Ah!
啊！
Ah~
哈~
Eh?!
呃！？
We need to talk
我们得谈谈
Ah!
啊！
Ren
Ren
I'm just gonna come out and say it
我要爬出衣柜告诉你
You, are one of my best friends
你，是我最好的朋友之一
These past few months, I feel like we've really bonded
过去这几个月，我觉得咱们真的心有灵犀
Even though you don't say much
尽管你是无口属性
I mean, you're really quiet
我是说，你真的很安静
To be perfectly honest, I don't know that much about you personally
说句老实话，我对你并不是很了解
But darn it, I consider you to be the brother I never had!
大爷的，我可是把你当成前所未有的兄弟啊！
And I you
彼此彼此
Which is why I wanted to get your advice on..
所以我就想跟你请教请教如何..
Girls
泡妹子
Girls?
妹子？
I just..don't know..
我只是..不懂..
how to..
如何..
girls..um, I..
妹子..哎呀，我..
I guess what I'm asking is..well
我觉得我想问的就是..好吧
How did you and Nora..you know
你和Nora是如何..懂吧
Uh..eh..em..
我竟..无言..以对..
We're not actually together-together
我们不是那种“在一起”啦
Nora, I said headphones on!
Nora我说了戴上耳机！
0w0
0w0
Jaune
Jaune
What is this all about?
到底怎么回事？
It's Weiss
是Weiss
I'm completely head over heels for her, and she won't even give me a chance
我对她已经神魂颠倒了，而她连机会都没留给我
She's cold
她冷如霜
But..she's also incredible
却又棒得不可思议
She's smart, and graceful, and..talented
她聪明，优雅，而且..有才
I mean, have you heard her sing?
话说你听过她唱歌么？
I just wish she'd take me seriously, you know
我只是希望她能认真对待我，知道么
I wish I could tell her how I feel, without messing it all up
我希望能向她传达自己的感情，而不是全都搞砸
Then do it
那就行动吧
Uh, what?
呃，啥？
Tell her exactly what you've just said
把你刚才的话原原本本告诉她
No ridiculous schemes
别玩可笑的花样
No pick up lines
不要油腔滑调
Just..be honest
你要..真诚
But..what if..
但..如果..
Jaune
Jaune
You can't get it wrong if it's the truth
真实的感情是不会被搞砸的
You're right
说得对
Thanks, Pyrrha
谢了，Pyrrha
Good talk, Ren!
聊得很愉快，Ren！
Practice what you preach, Pyrrha
你也要按自己说的去做啊，Pyrrha
Yang, if you're going to tell me to stop, you may as well just save your breath
Yang，如果你要我放弃，那还是别白费唇舌了
I don't want you to stop, I want you to slow down
我没要你放弃，我只想让你放慢节奏
We don't have the luxury to slow down
我们可没闲情逸致放慢节奏
It's not a luxury, it's a necessity
这不是闲情逸致，是必要举措
The necessity is stopping Torchwick
现在的必要举措就是阻止Torchwick
And we're going to
我们会阻止他的
But first you have to sit down and listen to what I have to say
但首先你得坐下听听我要说的话
Fine
好吧
Ruby and I grew up in Patch
Ruby和我在补丁岛长大
An island just off the coast of Vale
是溪谷海岸边的一个岛
Our parents were Huntsmen
我们的双亲是猎人
Our dad taught at Signal, and our mom took on missions around the kingdom
爸爸在信号教书，妈妈则在王国里执行任务
Her name was Summer Rose
她叫Summer Rose
And she was like..
简直就是个..
Super Mom
超级老妈
Baker of cookies and slayer of giant monsters
既能烤曲奇饼，也能砍大怪兽
And then..
然后..
One day she left for a mission and never came back
某天她去执行一个任务就再没回来了
It was tough
那些天很难熬
Ruby was really torn up, but..
Ruby的心都碎了，但..
I think she's still too young to really get what was going on, you know
我觉得她还太小，无法理解发生了什么
And my dad just kind of..shut down
而爸爸就直接..崩溃了
It wasn't long before I learned why
不久我就明白原因了
Summer wasn't the first love he lost
Summer并非他失去的第一个爱人
She was the second
她是第二个
The first..
第一个..
Was my mom
是我妈妈
He wouldn't tell me everything
他不告诉我所有事情
But I learned that the two of them had been on a team together with Summer and Qrow
但我得知了他们俩和Summer与Qrow都在一个小队
And that she'd left me with him just after I was born
而她刚生下我就把我留给爸爸
No one had seen her since
从此再也没人见过她
Why did she leave you?
她为什么离开你？
That question..
问得好..
Why?
为什么？
I didn't know the answer, but I was determined to find out
我不知道答案，但我决定要弄清楚
It was all I thought about
我当时只想了这么多
I would ask anybody I could what they knew about her
我会问遍所有人关于她的信息
Then, one day, I found something
之后某天，我发现了一个东西
What I thought was a clue that could lead me to answers
我认为这条线索能领我找到答案
or maybe even my mother
或甚至找到我母亲
I waited for Dad to leave the house, put Ruby in a wagon, and headed out
我等爸爸出门后，就把Ruby放在推车里启程了
I must've walked for hours
我肯定走了好几个小时
I had cuts and bruises, was totally exhausted
我全身伤痕累累，筋疲力尽
But I wasn't gonna let anything stop me
但我不会让任何事物阻止我
When we finally got there
我们终于到达了
I could barely stand
我都站不稳了
But I didn't care
但我不在意
I had made it
我办到了
And then I saw them
然后我就看见了它们
Those burning red eyes
那些火红的眼睛
There we were, a toddler sleeping in the back of a wagon and a stupid girl too exhausted to even cry for help
而我们，一个蹒跚学步的小孩睡在推车里，一个傻女孩累得连呼救的力气都没有
We might as well have been served on a silver platter
我们会被放在银盘子里端上餐桌吧
But, as luck would have it
但，幸运的是
Our uncle showed up just in time
我们的叔叔及时出现
My stubbornness should've gotten us killed that night
我的固执差点在那晚把我们害死
Yang..
Yang..
I'm sorry that happened to you
我很难过你发生了这些
And I understand what you're trying to tell me
而且我懂你想说的意思
But this is different
但这个不同
I'm not a child
我不是小孩
And this isn't just a search for answers, I can't just..
而且这也不是单纯地寻求答案，我不能..
I told you, I'm not telling you to stop
我说了，我不是要你放弃
I haven't
我也没放弃
To this day I still want to know what happened to my mother and why she left me
时至今日我依然想知道我母亲发生了什么和她离开我的原因
But I will never let that search control me
但我不会为这些调查走火入魔
We're going to find the answers we're looking for, Blake
我们会找到需要的答案的，Blake
But if we destroy ourselves in the process, what good are we?
但若在此过程中把自己弄垮了，有什么意义？
You don't understand
你不懂啊
I'm the only one who can do this!
我是唯一能胜任的人！
No, you don't understand
不，你才不懂
If Roman Torchwick walked through that door, what would you do?
如果Roman Torchwick穿过那扇门，你会怎么做？
I'd fight him!
我跟他战！
You'd lose!
你会输！
I can stop him!
我能推了他！
You can't even stop me!
你连我都推不动！
I'm not asking you to stop
我没要你放弃啊
Just please
但是求你了
Get some rest
休息一下吧
Not just for you
不仅为了你自己
But for the people you care about
也为了你关心的人们
And if you feel like coming out tomorrow
如果你明天想来的话
I'll save you a dance
我就给你留支舞
Neptune!
Neptune！
Oh, uh..hey, what's up?
噢呃..嘿，怎么了？
I know this is a little unorthodox, but..
我知道这有点古怪，不过..
I wanted to ask you something
我想求你一件事
Would you..like to accompany me to the dance tomorrow?
你是否..愿意明天跟我一起去舞会？
Oh, you look beautiful!
噢，你好漂亮啊！
Can we have a serious talk about how Weiss fights in these?
我们能探讨一下Weiss穿着这些是如何战斗的么？
Stupid..dumb..neck trap
这卡脖子的太二了
I knew you'd look better in a tie
我就知道你戴领带更好看
So, does this mean we're going..together?
所以，这表示我们是..舞伴咯？
Technically, though my first dance is spoken for
基本没错，不过我第一支舞有人订了
I told you she would come
我就说她会来的
Mission accomplished
任务完成
So, what do we do now?
那么，我们现在干什么？
Just have fun!
随便玩吧！
Does that mean I can change out of these stupid things and into my hood now?
那就是说我可以把这身蠢东西换下来，穿回兜帽咯？
Stupid lady stilts!
傻气的女式高跷！
Not enjoying yourself?
玩得不开心吗？
Oh! No..everything's fine
噢！没..挺好的
I'm just not much of a fancy pansy..dancey girl
只是我并非那种能华丽起舞的女孩
Well, you can't spend your entire life on the battlefield
但你也不能把一辈子都花在战场上
Even if you may want to
就算你真这么想
Yeah, that lesson's been floating around a lot lately
是啊，最近也总被人这样教育
If you think about it, fighting and dancing aren't so different
你仔细想想，战斗和跳舞其实区别并不大
Two partners interlocked..
两个搭档紧密相连..
Although..one wrong move on the ballroom merely leads to a swollen foot
尽管..舞池里走错一步只会肿起一只脚而已
Or a twisted ankle
或扭到脚踝
It's not every day that friends are able to come together like this
能这样把朋友们聚在一起的日子并不多
Time has a way of testing our bonds
时间有自己的方式考验我们的羁绊
But it's nights like these that can help keep them stronger than ever
但这样的夜晚却能让羁绊更加深厚
Nights like these are ones we'll never forget
这样的夜晚让人终身难忘
You guys are just in time
你们正好赶上
Wouldn't miss it for the world
天塌了也不会错过啊
BRB
BRB
This SUB is presented by Baidu RWBY Bar Creator: sbz_kid
本字幕由百度RWBY吧提供 片源/翻译/时间轴/特效/后期：sbz_kid